<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<elements><info><name>VARMonk</name><description>The Monk class from the Daniels Variant.</description><author>Torad</author><update version="1.0"><file url=" 

https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ToradDnD/Sea-Sorcerer/master/user-Torad/VARmonk.xml" name="class-VARmonk.xml"/></update></info><element name="VARMonk" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_MONK" 

source="Daniel Variant " type="Class"><description>
<p>Her fists a blur as they deflect an incoming hail of arrows, a half-elf springs over a barricade and throws herself into the massed ranks of hobgoblins on the other side. She whirls 

among them, knocking their blows aside and sending them reeling, until at last she stands alone.</p>
<p class="indent">Taking a deep breath, a human covered in tattoos settles into a battle stance. As the first charging orcs reach him, he exhales and a blast of fire roars from his mouth, 

engulfing his foes.</p>
<p class="indent">Moving with the silence of the night, a black-clad halfling steps into a shadow beneath an arch and emerges from another inky shadow on a balcony a stone’s throw away. 

She slides her blade free of its clothwrapped scabbard and peers through the open window at the tyrant prince, so vulnerable in the grip of sleep.</p>
<p class="indent">Whatever their discipline, monks are united in their ability to magically harness the energy that flows in their bodies. Whether channeled as a striking display of combat 

prowess or a subtler focus of defensive ability and speed, this energy infuses all that a monk does.</p>
<h4>THE MAGIC OF KI</h4>
<p>Monks make careful study of a magical energy that most monastic traditions call ki. This energy is an element of the magic that suffuses the multiverse—specifically, the element that 

flows through living bodies. Monks harness this power within themselves to create magical effects and exceed their bodies’ physical capabilities, and some of their special attacks can 

hinder the flow of ki in their opponents. Using this energy, monks channel uncanny speed and strength into their unarmed strikes. As they gain experience, their martial training and their 

mastery of ki gives them more power over their bodies and the bodies of their foes.</p>
<h4>TRAINING AND ASCETICISM</h4>
<p>Small walled cloisters dot the landscapes of the worlds of DnD, tiny refuges from the flow of ordinary life, where time seems to stand still. The monks who live there seek personal 

perfection through contemplation and rigorous training. Many entered the monastery as children, sent to live there when their parents died, when food couldn’t be found to support them, or 

in return for some kindness that the monks had performed for their families.</p>
<p class="indent">Some monks live entirely apart from the surrounding population, secluded from anything that might impede their spiritual progress. Others are sworn to isolation, emerging 

only to serve as spies or assassins at the command of their leader, a noble patron, or some other mortal or divine power.</p>
<p class="indent">The majority of monks don’t shun their neighbors, making frequent visits to nearby towns or villages and exchanging their service for food and other goods. As versatile 

warriors, monks often end up protecting their neighbors from monsters or tyrants.</p>
<p class="indent">For a monk, becoming an adventurer means leaving a structured, communal lifestyle to become a wanderer. This can be a harsh transition, and monks don’t undertake it 

lightly. Those who leave their cloisters take their work seriously, approaching their adventures as personal tests of their physical and spiritual growth. As a rule, monks care little for 

material wealth and are driven by a desire to accomplish a greater mission than merely slaying monsters and plundering their treasure.</p>
<h4>CREATING A MONK</h4>
<p>As you make your monk character, think about your connection to the monastery where you learned your skills and spent your formative years. Were you an orphan or a child left on the 

monastery’s threshold? Did your parents promise you to the monastery in gratitude for a service performed by the monks? Did you enter this secluded life to hide from a crime you committed? 

Or did you choose the monastic life for yourself?</p>
<p class="indent">Consider why you left. Did the head of your monastery choose you for a particularly important mission beyond the cloister? Perhaps you were cast out because of some 

violation of the community’s rules. Did you dread leaving, or were you happy to go? Is there something you hope to accomplish outside the monastery? Are you eager to return to your home?

</p>
<p class="indent">As a result of the structured life of a monastic community and the discipline required to harness ki, monks are almost always lawful in alignment.</p>
<h5 class="caption">QUICK BUILD</h5>
<p>You can make a monk quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Dexterity your highest ability score, followed by Wisdom. Second, choose the hermit background.</p>
<h3>CLASS FEATURES</h3>
<p>As a monk, you gain the following class features.</p>
<h5 class="caption">HIT POINTS</h5>
<ul class="unstyled">
<li><strong>Hit Dice:</strong> 1d8 per monk level</li>
<li><strong>Hit Points at 1st Level:</strong> 8 + your Constitution modifier</li>
<li><strong>Hit Points at Higher Levels:</strong> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per monk level after 1st</li>
</ul>
<h5 class="caption">PROFICIENCIES</h5>
<ul class="unstyled mb">
<li><strong>Armor:</strong> None</li>
<li><strong>Weapons:</strong> Simple weapons, shortswords, improvised weapons</li>
<li><strong>Tools:</strong> Choose one type of artisan’s tools or one musical instrument</li>
</ul>
<ul class="unstyled">
<li><strong>Saving Throws:</strong> Strength, Dexterity</li>
<li><strong>Skills:</strong> Choose two from Acrobatics, Athletics, History, Insight, Religion, and Stealth</li>
</ul>
<h5 class="caption">EQUIPMENT</h5>
<p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
<ul>
<li>(a) a shortsword or (b) any simple weapon</li>
<li>(a) a dungeoneer’s pack or (b) an explorer’s pack</li>
<li>10 darts</li>
</ul>
<h5 class="caption">THE MONK</h5>
<table class="class-features"><thead>
<tr>
<td class="col-10">Level</td>	<td class="col-10">Martial Arts</td>	<td class="col-10">Ki Points</td>	<td class="col-10">Unarmored Movement</td>	<td class="col-60 

left">Features</td>
</tr></thead>
<tr>
<td>1st</td>	<td>1d4</td>	<td>—</td>	<td>—</td>	<td class="left">Unarmored Defense, Martial Arts</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2nd</td>	<td>1d4</td>	<td>4</td>	<td>+10 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Ki, Unarmored Movement</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3rd</td>	<td>1d4</td>	<td>5</td>	<td>+10 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Monastic Tradition, Deflect Missiles</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4th</td>	<td>1d4</td>	<td>6</td>	<td>+10 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Ability Score Improvement, Slow Fall</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5th</td>	<td>1d6</td>	<td>7</td>	<td>+10 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Extra Attack, Stunning Strike</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6th</td>	<td>1d6</td>	<td>8</td>	<td>+15 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Ki-Empowered Strikes, Monastic Tradition feature</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7th</td>	<td>1d6</td>	<td>9</td>	<td>+15 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Evasion, Stillness of Mind</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>8th</td>	<td>1d6</td>	<td>10</td>	<td>+15 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>9th</td>	<td>1d8</td>	<td>11</td>	<td>+15 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Unarmored Movement improvement</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>10th</td>	<td>1d8</td>	<td>12</td>	<td>+20 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Purity of Body</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>11th</td>	<td>1d8</td>	<td>13</td>	<td>+20 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Monastic Tradition feature</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>12th</td>	<td>1d8</td>	<td>14</td>	<td>+20 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>13th</td>	<td>1d10</td>	<td>15</td>	<td>+20 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Tongue of the Sun and Moon</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>14th</td>	<td>1d10</td>	<td>16</td>	<td>+25 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Diamond Soul</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>15th</td>	<td>1d10</td>	<td>17</td>	<td>+25 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Timeless Body</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>16th</td>	<td>1d10</td>	<td>18</td>	<td>+25 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>17th</td>	<td>1d12</td>	<td>19</td>	<td>+25 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Monastic Tradition feature</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>18th</td>	<td>1d12</td>	<td>20</td>	<td>+30 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Empty Body</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>19th</td>	<td>1d12</td>	<td>21</td>	<td>+30 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Ability Score Improvement</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>20th</td>	<td>1d12</td>	<td>22</td>	<td>+30 ft.</td>	<td class="left">Perfect Self</td>
</tr></table>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_UNARMORED_DEFENSE"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_MARTIAL_ARTS"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_UNARMORED_MOVEMENT"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_MONASTIC_TRADITION"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_DEFLECT_MISSILES"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_MONK"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_SLOW_FALL"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_EXTRA_ATTACK_MONK"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_STUNNING_STRIKE"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI_EMPOWERED_STRIKES"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_EVASION_MONK"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_STILLNESS_OF_MIND"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_PURITY_OF_BODY"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_TONGUE_OF_THE_SUN_AND_MOON"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_DIAMOND_SOUL"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_TIMELESS_BODY_MONK"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_EMPTY_BODY"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_PERFECT_SELF"/>
</description><sheet display="false"><description>A master of martial arts, harnessing the power of the body in pursuit of physical and spiritual 

perfection.</description></sheet><setters><set name="short">A master of martial arts, harnessing the power of the body in pursuit of physical and spiritual perfection.</set><set 

name="hd">d8</set></setters>
  <rules><grant id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" type="Proficiency" requirements="!ID_TORAD_MULTICLASS_VARMONK"/><grant 

id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" type="Proficiency" requirements="!ID_TORAD_MULTICLASS_VARMONK"/> <grant id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" type="Proficiency" 

requirements="!ID_TORAD_MULTICLASS_VARMONK"/>
  <grant id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" type="Proficiency" requirements="!ID_TORAD_MULTICLASS_VARMONK"/> 
   <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_UNARMORED_DEFENSE" type="Class Feature" level="1"/>
  <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_MARTIAL_ARTS" type="Class Feature" level="1"/>
 <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI" type="Class Feature" level="2"/>
    <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_UNARMORED_MOVEMENT" type="Class Feature" level="2"/>
    <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_MONASTIC_TRADITION" type="Class Feature" level="3"/>
    <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_DEFLECT_MISSILES" type="Class Feature" level="3"/>
    <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_MONK" type="Class Feature" level="4"/>
    <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_SLOW_FALL" type="Class Feature" level="4"/>
    <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_EXTRA_ATTACK_MONK" type="Class Feature" level="5"/>
    <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_STUNNING_STRIKE" type="Class Feature" level="5"/>
    <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI_EMPOWERED_STRIKES" type="Class Feature" level="6"/>
    <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_EVASION_MONK" type="Class Feature" level="7"/>
    <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_STILLNESS_OF_MIND" type="Class Feature" level="7"/>
    <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_PURITY_OF_BODY" type="Class Feature" level="10"/>
    <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_TONGUE_OF_THE_SUN_AND_MOON" type="Class Feature" level="13"/>
    <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_DIAMOND_SOUL" type="Class Feature" level="14"/>
    <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_TIMELESS_BODY_MONK" type="Class Feature" level="15"/>
    <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_EMPTY_BODY" type="Class Feature" level="18"/>
    <grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_PERFECT_SELF" type="Class Feature" level="20"/></rules>
<multiclass id="ID_TORAD_MULTICLASS_VARMONK"><prerequisite>Dexterity 13 and Wisdom 13</prerequisite><requirements>([dex:13],[wis:13])</requirements><setters><set name="multiclass 

proficiencies">Simple weapons, shortswords</set></setters><rules><grant id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" type="Grants"/><grant id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" 

type="Proficiency"/><grant id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" type="Proficiency"/></rules></multiclass></element>
 <element name="Unarmored Defense" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_UNARMORED_DEFENSE" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class Feature"><description>
<p>Beginning at 1st level, while you are wearing no armor and not wielding a shield, your AC equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Wisdom modifier. When you get hit by an attack you 

can use your reaction to roll a martial arts die, increasing your AC against that attack by the number rolled, potentially causing the attack to miss.</p>
</description><sheet><description>While you are wearing no armor and not wielding a shield, your AC equals {{ac:unarmored defense monk}}. When you get hit by an attack you can use your 

reaction to roll a 1d{{martial arts:dice}}, increasing your AC against that attack by the number rolled.</description></sheet><rules><stat name="ac:unarmored defense monk:base" 

value="10"/><stat name="ac:unarmored defense monk:dexterity" value="dexterity:modifier"/><stat name="ac:unarmored defense monk:wisdom" value="wisdom:modifier"/><stat name="ac:unarmored 

defense monk" value="ac:unarmored defense monk:base"/><stat name="ac:unarmored defense monk" value="ac:unarmored defense monk:dexterity"/><stat name="ac:unarmored defense monk" 

value="ac:unarmored defense monk:wisdom"/><stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:unarmored defense monk" alt="Unarmored Defense (Monk)" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" 

bonus="calculation"/></rules></element><element name="Martial Arts" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_MARTIAL_ARTS" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class Feature"><description>
<p>At 1st level, your practice of martial arts gives you mastery of combat styles that use unarmed strikes and monk weapons, which are shortswords and any simple melee weapons that don’t 

have the two-handed or heavy property and improvised weapons.</p>
<p class="indent">You gain the following benefits while you are unarmed or wielding only monk weapons and you aren’t wearing armor or wielding a shield:</p>
<ul>
•	<li>You can use Dexterity instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes and monk weapons.</li>
•	<li>You can roll a d4 in place of the normal damage of your unarmed strike or monk weapon. This die changes as you gain monk levels, as shown in the Martial Arts column of the Monk 

table.</li>
•	<li>When you use the Attack action with an unarmed strike or a monk weapon or use Ki points during your action on your turn, you can make one unarmed strike as a bonus action. For 

example, if you take the Attack action and attack with a quarterstaff, you can also make an unarmed strike as a bonus action, assuming you haven’t already taken a bonus action this 

turn.</li>
</ul>
<p>Certain monasteries use specialized forms of the monk weapons. For example, you might use a club that is two lengths of wood connected by a short chain (called a nunchaku) or a sickle 

with a shorter, straighter blade (called a kama). Whatever name you use for a monk weapon, you can use the game statistics provided for the weapon.</p>
</description><sheet><description>Your unarmed strike does 1d{{martial arts:dice}}+{{martial arts:damage}} damage. You can use Strength or Dexterity for these attacks. When you use the 

Attack action with an unarmed strike or a monk weapon or spend Ki during your action on your turn, you can make one unarmed strike as a bonus action. For example, if you take the Attack 

action and attack with a quarterstaff, you can also make an unarmed strike as a bonus action, assuming you haven’t already taken a bonus action this turn.</description></sheet><rules><stat 

name="martial arts:attack" value="strength:modifier" bonus="martial arts"/><stat name="martial arts:attack" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="martial arts"/><stat name="martial 

arts:damage" value="strength:modifier" bonus="martial arts"/><stat name="martial arts:damage" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="martial arts"/><stat name="martial arts:dice" value="4" 

bonus="martial arts"/><stat name="martial arts:dice" level="5" value="6" bonus="martial arts"/><stat name="martial arts:dice" level="9" value="8" bonus="martial arts"/><stat name="martial 

arts:dice" level="13" value="10" bonus="martial arts"/><stat name="martial arts:dice" level="17" value="12" bonus="martial arts"/></rules></element><element name="Ki" 

id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class Feature"><description>
<p>Starting at 2nd level, your training allows you to harness the mystic energy of ki. Your access to this energy is represented by a number of ki points. Your monk level determines the 

number of points you have, as shown in the Ki Points column of the Monk table.</p>
<p class="indent">You can spend these points to fuel various ki features. You start knowing three such features: Flurry of Blows, Patient Defense, and Step of the Wind. You learn more ki 

features as you gain levels in this class.</p>
<p class="indent">When you spend a ki point, it is unavailable until you finish a short or long rest, at the end of which you draw all of your expended ki back into yourself. You must 

spend at least 30 minutes of the rest meditating to regain your ki points.</p>
<p class="indent">Some of your ki features require your target to make a saving throw to resist the feature’s effects. The saving throw DC is calculated as follows:</p>
<center>
<p><strong>Ki save DC</strong> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</p>
</center>
<h6>FLURRY OF BLOWS</h6>
<p>Immediately after you take the Attack action or spend Ki during your action on your turn, you can spend 1 ki point to make two unarmed strikes as a bonus action. Once you reach level 11 

you can choose to spend 2 Ki points and make 3 unarmed strikes as a bonus action instead.</p>
<h6>PATIENT DEFENSE</h6>
<p>You can spend 1 ki point to take the Dodge action as a bonus action on your turn. You can spend 3 Ki Points to take the Dodge action as a reaction when an enemy attempts to attack you 

(but before he rolls his attack) or before you make a dexterity saving throw.</p>
<h6>STEP OF THE WIND</h6>
<p>You can spend 1 ki point to take the Disengage or Dash action as a bonus action on your turn, and your jump distance is doubled for the turn. You can spend 3 ki points to take the 

Disengage and the Dash action as one bonus action and your jump distance is doubled for the turn.</p>
</description><sheet><description>You have {{ki:points}} Ki Points and your Ki DC is {{ki:dc}}</description></sheet><rules><stat name="ki:points" value="level:VARmonk"/><stat name = 

"ki:points" value = "2" /><stat name="ki:dc" value="8"/><stat name="ki:dc" value="proficiency"/><stat name="ki:dc" value="wisdom:modifier"/><grant 

id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI_FLURRY_OF_BLOWS" type="Class Feature"/><grant id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI_PATIENT_DEFENSE" type="Class Feature"/><grant 

id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI_STEP_OF_THE_WIND" type="Class Feature"/></rules></element><element name="Flurry of Blows" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI_FLURRY_OF_BLOWS" 

source="Daniel Variants" type="Class Feature"><description>
<p> Immediately after you take the Attack action or spend Ki during your action on your turn, you can spend 1 ki point to make two unarmed strikes as a bonus action. 
</p></description><description level="11"><p> Immediately after you take the Attack action or spend Ki during your action on your turn, you can spend 1 ki point to make two unarmed strikes 

as a bonus action. You can choose to spend 2 Ki points and make 3 unarmed strikes as a bonus action instead.</p></description><sheet usage="Ki" action="Bonus Action"><description> 

Immediately after you take the Attack action or spend Ki during your action on your turn, you can spend 1 ki point to make two unarmed strikes as a bonus action. </description><description 

level="11"><p> Immediately after you take the Attack action or spend Ki during your action on your turn, you can spend 1 ki point to make two unarmed strikes as a bonus action. You can 

choose to spend 2 Ki points and make 3 unarmed strikes as a bonus action instead.</p></description></sheet></element>
<element name="Patient Defense" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI_PATIENT_DEFENSE" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class Feature"><description>
<p>You can spend 1 ki point to take the Dodge action as a bonus action on your turn. You can spend 3 Ki Points to take the Dodge action as a reaction when an enemy attempts to attack you 

(but before he rolls his attack) or before you make a dexterity saving throw.</p>
</description><sheet usage="Ki" action="Bonus Action"><description>You can spend 1 ki point to take the Dodge action on your turn. You can spend 3 Ki Points to take the Dodge action as a 

reaction when an enemy attempts to attack you (but before he rolls his attack) or before you make a dexterity saving throw.</description></sheet></element><element name="Step of the Wind" 

id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI_STEP_OF_THE_WIND" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class Feature"><description>
<p>You can spend 1 ki point to take the Disengage or Dash action as a bonus action on your turn, and your jump distance is doubled for the turn. You can spend 3 ki points to take the 

Disengage and the Dash action as one bonus action and your jump distance is doubled for the turn.</p>
</description><sheet usage="Ki" action="Bonus Action"><description>You can spend 1 ki point to take the Disengage or Dash action on your turn, and your jump distance is doubled for the 

turn. You can spend 3 ki points to take the Disengage and the Dash action as one bonus action and your jump distance is doubled for the turn.</description></sheet></element><element 

name="Unarmored Movement" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_UNARMORED_MOVEMENT" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class Feature"><description>
<p>Starting at 2nd level, your speed increases by 10 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield. This bonus increases when you reach certain monk levels, as shown in the 

Monk table. While you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield you can spend 1 ki points as a bonus action. For the next 10 Minutes you can use your Dexterity score (and acrobatics 

skill) instead of strength for Grappling and Athletics chekcs as well as jump distance calculations.</p>
<p class="indent">At 9th level, you gain the ability to move along vertical surfaces and across liquids or even along ceilings on your turn without falling during the move.</p>
</description><sheet><description>Your speed increases by {{monk:unarmored movement}} feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield. While you are not wearing armor or wielding 

a shield you can spend 1 ki points as a bonus action. For the next 10 Minutes you can use your Dexterity score (and acrobatics skill) instead of strength for Grappling and Athletics chekcs 

as well as jump distance calculations.</description><description level="9">Your speed increases by {{monk:unarmored movement}} feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield. 

You gain the ability to move along vertical surfaces and across liquids or even along ceilings on your turn without falling during the move. While you are not wearing armor or wielding a 

shield you can spend 1 ki points as a bonus action. For the next 10 Minutes you can use your Dexterity score (and acrobatics skill) instead of strength for Grappling and Athletics chekcs 

as well as jump distance calculations.</description></sheet><rules><stat name="monk:unarmored movement" level="2" value="10" bonus="unarmored movement"/><stat name="monk:unarmored 

movement" level="6" value="15" bonus="unarmored movement"/><stat name="monk:unarmored movement" level="10" value="20" bonus="unarmored movement"/><stat name="monk:unarmored movement" 

level="14" value="25" bonus="unarmored movement"/><stat name="monk:unarmored movement" level="18" value="30" bonus="unarmored movement"/><stat name="innate speed:misc" 

requirements="[innate speed:1]" value="monk:unarmored movement" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" bonus="unarmored movement"/><stat name="innate speed:climb:misc" requirements="[innate 

speed:climb:1]" value="monk:unarmored movement" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" bonus="unarmored movement"/><stat name="innate speed:fly:misc" requirements="[innate speed:fly:1]" 

value="monk:unarmored movement" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" bonus="unarmored movement"/><stat name="innate speed:swim:misc" requirements="[innate speed:swim:1]" 

value="monk:unarmored movement" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" bonus="unarmored movement"/><stat name="innate speed:burrow:misc" requirements="[innate speed:burrow:1]" 

value="monk:unarmored movement" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" bonus="unarmored movement"/></rules></element><element name="Monastic Tradition" 

id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_MONASTIC_TRADITION" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class Feature"><description>
<p>When you reach 3rd level, you commit yourself to a monastic tradition, such as the Way of the Open Hand. Your tradition grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th, 11th, and 17th 

level.</p>
</description><sheet display="false"/><rules><select name="Monastic Tradition" type="Archetype" supports="VARMonastic Tradition"/>  </rules></element><element name="Deflect Missiles" 

id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_DEFLECT_MISSILES" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class Feature"><description>
<p>Starting at 3rd level, you can use your reaction to deflect or catch the missile when you are hit by a ranged weapon attack. When you do so, the damage you take from the attack is 

reduced by 1d10 + your Dexterity modifier + your monk level and you gain the benefits of half cover until  the end of your next turn. </p>
<p class="indent">If you reduce the damage to 0, you can catch the missile if it is small enough for you to hold in one hand and you have at least one hand free. If you catch a missile in 

this way, you can spend 1 ki point to make a ranged attack with the weapon or piece of ammunition you just caught, as part of the same reaction. You make this attack with proficiency, 

regardless of your weapon proficiencies, and the missile counts as a monk weapon for the attack.</p>
</description><sheet action="Reaction"><description>You can deflect or catch the missile when you are hit by a ranged weapon attack. When you do so, the damage you take from the attack is 

reduced by 1d10+{{monk:deflect missiles bonus}} and you gain the benefits of half cover until the end of your next turn. If you reduce the damage to 0, you can catch the missile if it is 

small enough for you to hold in one hand and you have at least one hand free. If you catch a missile in this way, you can spend 1 ki point to make a ranged attack with the weapon or piece 

of ammunition you just caught, as part of the same reaction. You make this attack with proficiency, regardless of your weapon proficiencies, and the missile counts as a monk weapon for the 

attack.</description></sheet><rules><stat name="monk:deflect missiles bonus" value="dexterity:modifier"/><stat name="monk:deflect missiles bonus" 

value="level:VARmonk"/></rules></element><element name="Ability Score Improvement" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_MONK" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class 

Feature"><compendium display="false"/><description>
<p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 

1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
</description><sheet display="false"/><rules>  <select name="Improvement Option (Monk 4)" type="Class Feature" supports="Improvement Option,Monk,4" level="4"/>

<select name="Improvement Option (Monk 8)" type="Class Feature" supports="Improvement Option,Monk,8" level="8"/>

<select name="Improvement Option (Monk 12)" type="Class Feature" supports="Improvement Option,Monk,12" level="12"/>

<select name="Improvement Option (Monk 16)" type="Class Feature" supports="Improvement Option,Monk,16" level="16"/>

<select name="Improvement Option (Monk 19)" type="Class Feature" supports="Improvement Option,Monk,19" level="19"/>    </rules></element><element name="Slow Fall" 

id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_SLOW_FALL" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class Feature"><description>
<p>Beginning at 4th level, you can use your reaction when you fall to reduce any falling damage you take by an amount equal to five times your monk level.</p>
</description><sheet usage="Reaction"><description>Reduce any falling damage you take by {{monk:slowfall}}.</description></sheet><rules><stat name="monk:slowfall" 

value="level:VARmonk"/><stat name="monk:slowfall" value="level:VARmonk"/><stat name="monk:slowfall" value="level:VARmonk"/><stat name="monk:slowfall" value="level:VARmonk"/><stat 

name="monk:slowfall" value="level:VARmonk"/></rules></element><element name="Extra Attack" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_EXTRA_ATTACK_MONK" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class 

Feature"><description>
<p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
</description><sheet><description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description></sheet><rules><stat name="extra attack:count" 

level="5" value="2" bonus="extra attack"/></rules></element>
<element name="Stunning Strike" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_STUNNING_STRIKE" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class Feature"><description>
<p>Starting at 5th level, you can interfere with the flow of ki in an opponent’s body. When you hit another creature with a melee attack, you can spend 1 ki point to attempt a stunning 

strike. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be stunned until the end of your next turn. If the target succeeds on the saving throw you cannot use this feature against 

that creature again until the beginning of your next turn.</p>
</description><sheet usage="Ki"><description>When you hit another creature with a melee weapon attack, you can spend 1 ki point to attempt a stunning strike. The target must succeed on a 

Constitution saving throw or be stunned until the end of your next turn. If the target succeeds on the saving throw you cannot use this feature against that creature again until the 

beginning of your next turn.</description></sheet></element><element name="Ki-Empowered Strikes" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_KI_EMPOWERED_STRIKES" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class 

Feature"><description>
<p>Starting at 6th level, your unarmed strikes count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
</description><sheet><description>Your unarmed strikes count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and 

damage.</description></sheet></element><element name="Evasion" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_EVASION_MONK" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class Feature"><description>
<p>At 7th level, your instinctive agility lets you dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a blue dragon’s lightning breath or a fireball spell. When you are subjected to an 

effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</p>
</description><sheet><description>When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed 

on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</description></sheet></element><element name="Stillness of Mind" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_STILLNESS_OF_MIND" source="Daniel 

Variants" type="Class Feature"><description>
<p>Starting at 7th level, you can use your action to end one effect on yourself that is causing you to be charmed or frightened.</p>
</description><sheet action="Action"><description>You can end one effect on yourself that is causing you to be charmed or frightened.</description></sheet></element><element name="Purity 

of Body" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_PURITY_OF_BODY" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class Feature"><description>
<p>At 10th level, your mastery of the ki flowing through you makes you immune to disease and poison. In addition you can use your action to regain Ki Points equal to your wisdom modifier. 

You then have to finish a long rest before you do so again</p>
</description><sheet><description>Your mastery of the ki flowing through you makes you immune to disease and poison. In addition you can use your action to regain {{wisdom:modifier}} Ki 

Points. You then must finish a long rest before you do so again. </description></sheet></element><element name="Tongue of the Sun and Moon" 

id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_TONGUE_OF_THE_SUN_AND_MOON" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class Feature"><description>
<p>Starting at 13th level, you learn to touch the ki of other minds so that you understand all spoken languages. Moreover, if you want to any creature that can understand a language can 

understand what you say.</p>
</description><sheet><description>You learn to touch the ki of other minds so that you understand all spoken languages. Moreover, if you want to any creature that can understand a language 

can understand what you say.</description></sheet></element><element name="Diamond Soul" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_DIAMOND_SOUL" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class 

Feature"><description>
<p>Beginning at 14th level, your mastery of ki grants you proficiency in all saving throws.</p>
<p class="indent">Additionally, whenever you make a saving throw and fail, you can spend 1 ki point to reroll it and take the second result.</p>
</description><sheet usage="Ki"><description>Whenever you make a saving throw and fail, you can spend 1 ki point to reroll it and take the second result.</description></sheet><rules><grant 

id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" type="Proficiency"/><grant id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" type="Proficiency"/><grant id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CONSTITUTION" 

type="Proficiency"/><grant id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_INTELLIGENCE" type="Proficiency"/><grant id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" type="Proficiency"/><grant 

id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA" type="Proficiency"/></rules></element><element name="Timeless Body" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_TIMELESS_BODY_MONK" source="Daniel Variants" 

type="Class Feature"><description>
<p>At 15th level, your ki sustains you so that you suffer none of the frailty of old age, and you can’t be aged magically. You can still die of old age, however. In addition, you no longer 

need food or water and you can finish a long rest within a 4 hour meditation.</p>
</description><sheet><description>Your ki sustains you so that you suffer none of the frailty of old age, and you can’t be aged magically. You no longer need food or water and you can 

finish a long rest within a 4 hour meditation.</description></sheet></element><element name="Empty Body" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_EMPTY_BODY" source="Daniel Variants" type="Class 

Feature"><description>
<p>Beginning at 18th level, you can use your action to spend 4 ki points to become invisible for 1 minute. During that time, you also have resistance to all damage but force damage.</p>
<p class="indent">Additionally, you can spend 8 ki points to cast the astral projection spell, without needing material components. When you do so, you can’t take any other creatures with 

you.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_ASTRAL_PROJECTION"/>
</div>
</description><sheet usage="Ki" action="Action"><description>You can spend 4 ki points to become invisible for 1 minute. During that time, you also have resistance to all damage but force 

damage. You can spend 8 ki points to cast the astral projection spell, without needing material components. When you do so, you can’t take any other creatures with 

you.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ASTRAL_PROJECTION" type="Spell"/></rules></element><element name="Perfect Self" id="ID_TORAD_CLASS_FEATURE_MONK_PERFECT_SELF" 

source="Daniel Variants" type="Class Feature"><description>
<p>At 20th level, when you start your turn with less than 4 Ki, you regain ki until you have 4 Ki.</p>
</description><sheet><description> When you start your turn with less than 4 Ki, you regain ki until you have 4 Ki.</description></sheet></element><element name="Way of the Open Hand" 

id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_WAY_OF_THE_OPEN_HAND" source="Daniel Varaints" type="Archetype"><supports>VARMonastic Tradition</supports><description>
<p>Monks of the Way of the Open Hand are the ultimate masters of martial arts combat, whether armed or unarmed. They learn techniques to push and trip their opponents, manipulate ki to 

heal damage to their bodies, and practice advanced meditation that can protect them from harm.</p>
<div element="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAYOFTHEOPENHAND_OPEN_HAND_TECHNIQUE"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAYOFTHEOPENHAND_WHOLENESS_OF_BODY"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAYOFTHEOPENHAND_TRANQUILITY"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAYOFTHEOPENHAND_QUIVERING_PALM"/>
</description><sheet display="false"><description>The ultimate masters of martial arts combat, whether armed or unarmed.</description></sheet><rules><grant 

id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAYOFTHEOPENHAND_OPEN_HAND_TECHNIQUE" type="Archetype Feature" level="3"/><grant id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAYOFTHEOPENHAND_WHOLENESS_OF_BODY" 

type="Archetype Feature" level="6"/><grant id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAYOFTHEOPENHAND_TRANQUILITY" type="Archetype Feature" level="11"/><grant 

id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAYOFTHEOPENHAND_QUIVERING_PALM" type="Archetype Feature" level="17"/></rules></element><element name="Open Hand Technique" 

id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAYOFTHEOPENHAND_OPEN_HAND_TECHNIQUE" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><description>
<p>Starting when you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you can manipulate your enemy’s ki when you harness your own. Whenever you hit a creature with one of the attacks granted by your 

Flurry of Blows, you can impose one of the following effects on that target:</p>
<ul>
•	<li>It must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or be knocked prone.</li>
•	<li>It must make a Strength saving throw. If it fails, you can push it up to 15 feet away from you.</li>
•	<li>It can’t take reactions until the end of your next turn.</li>
</ul>
</description><sheet><description>Whenever you hit a creature with one of the attacks granted by your Flurry of Blows, you can impose one of the following effects on that target: knock 

prone DEX Save, Push 15 feet STR Save, It can’t take reactions until the end of your next turn.</description></sheet></element><element name="Wholeness of Body" 

id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAYOFTHEOPENHAND_WHOLENESS_OF_BODY" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><description>
<p>At 6th level, you gain the ability to heal yourself. At the start of your turn, you can regain hit points equal to your monk level. You must finish a short or long rest before you can 

use this feature again.</p>
</description><sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action"><description>You can regain {{level:VARmonk}} hit points.</description></sheet><rules></rules></element>
<element name="Tranquility" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAYOFTHEOPENHAND_TRANQUILITY" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><description>
<p>Beginning at 11th level, you can enter a special meditation that surrounds you with an aura of peace. At the end of a short or long rest, you gain the effect of a sanctuary spell that 

lasts until the end of your next short or long rest (the spell can end early as normal). The saving throw DC for the spell equals 8 + your Wisdom modifier + your proficiency bonus. As an 

action, you can dismiss the spell. For the next minute whenever you use your flurry of blows you can make one additional attack as part of the same bonus action. Once you dismissed the 

spell this way you need to finish a long rest before you can do so again.</p>
</description><sheet><description>At the end of a long rest, you gain the effect of a sanctuary spell that lasts until the start of your next long rest (the spell can end early as normal). 

The saving throw DC for the spell equals {{tranquility:dc}}. As an action, you can dismiss the spell. For the next minute whenever you use your flurry of blows you can make one additional 

attack as part of the same bonus action. Once you dismissed the spell this way you need to finish a long rest before you can do so again.</description></sheet><rules><stat 

name="tranquility:dc" value="8"/><stat name="tranquility:dc" value="proficiency"/><stat name="tranquility:dc" value="wisdom:modifier"/></rules></element><element name="Quivering Palm" 

id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAYOFTHEOPENHAND_QUIVERING_PALM" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><description>
<p>At 17th level, you gain the ability to set up lethal vibrations in someone’s body. When you hit a creature with an unarmed strike, you can spend 3 ki points to start these imperceptible 

vibrations, which last for a number of days equal to your monk level. The vibrations are harmless unless you use your action to end them. To do so, you and the target must be on the same 

plane of existence. When you use this action, the creature takes 10d10 necrotic damage and must make a Constitution saving throw. If it fails, it is reduced to 0 hit points if it has less 

than a 100 hitpoints remaining or takes 100 damage if it has more hitpoints remaining.</p>
<p class="indent">You can have only one creature under the effect of this feature at a time. You can choose to end the vibrations harmlessly without using an action.</p>
</description><sheet><description>When you hit a creature with an unarmed strike, you can spend 3 ki points to start these imperceptible vibrations, which last for {{level:VARmonk}} days. 

The vibrations are harmless unless you use your action to end them. To do so, you and the target must be on the same plane of existence. When you use this action, the creature takes 10d10 

necrotic damage and must make a Constitution saving throw. If it fails, it is reduced to 0 hit points if it has less than a 100 hitpoints remaining or takes 100 damage if it has more 

hitpoints remaining. You can have only one creature under the effect of this feature at a time. You can choose to end the vibrations harmlessly without using an 

action.</description></sheet></element>
<element name="Way of Shadow" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_MONK_WAY_OF_SHADOW" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype"><supports>VARMonastic Tradition</supports><description>
<p>Monks of the Way of Shadow follow a tradition that values stealth and subterfuge. These monks might be called ninjas or shadowdancers, and they serve as spies and assassins. Sometimes 

the members of a ninja monastery are family members, forming a clan sworn to secrecy about their arts and missions. Other monasteries are more like thieves’ guilds, hiring out their 

services to nobles, rich merchants, or anyone else who can pay their fees. Regardless of their methods, the heads of these monasteries expect the unquestioning obedience of their 

students.</p>
<div element="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_SHADOW_SHADOW_ARTS"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_SHADOW_SHADOW_STEP"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_SHADOW_CLOAK_OF_SHADOWS"/>
<div element="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_SHADOW_OPPORTUNIST"/>
</description><sheet display="false"><description>Monks of the Way of Shadow follow a tradition that values stealth and subterfuge.</description></sheet><rules><grant 

id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_SHADOW_SHADOW_ARTS" type="Archetype Feature" level="3"/><grant id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_SHADOW_SHADOW_STEP" type="Archetype Feature" 

level="6"/><grant id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_SHADOW_CLOAK_OF_SHADOWS" type="Archetype Feature" level="11"/><grant id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_SHADOW_OPPORTUNIST" 

type="Archetype Feature" level="17"/></rules></element><element name="Shadow Arts" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_SHADOW_SHADOW_ARTS" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype 

Feature"><description>
<p>Starting when you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you can use your ki to duplicate the effects of certain spells. As an action, you can spend 2 ki points to cast darkness, 

darkvision, pass without trace, or silence, without providing material components. When you cast darkness with this feature you can spend 1 additional ki point. If you do so you can see 

through the darkness you create. Additionally, you gain the minor illusion cantrip if you don’t already know it.</p>
</description><sheet usage="Ki" action="Action"><description>You can spend 2 ki points to cast darkness, darkvision, pass without trace, or silence, without providing material components. 

When you cast darkness with this feature you can spend 1 additional ki point. If you do so you can see through the darkness you create. Additionally, you gain the minor illusion cantrip if 

you don’t already know it.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MINOR_ILLUSION" type="Spell"/></rules></element><element name="Shadow Step" 

id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_SHADOW_SHADOW_STEP" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><description>
<p>At 6th level, you gain the ability to step from one shadow into another. When you are in dim light or darkness, as a bonus action you can teleport up to 60 feet to an unoccupied space 

you can see that is also in dim light or darkness. You then have advantage on the first melee attack you make before the end of the turn.</p>
</description><sheet action="Bonus Action"><description>When you are in dim light or darkness, you can teleport up to 60 feet to an unoccupied space you can see that is also in dim light 

or darkness. You then have advantage on the first melee attack you make before the end of the turn.</description></sheet></element><element name="Cloak of Shadows" 

id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_SHADOW_CLOAK_OF_SHADOWS" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><description>
<p>By 11th level, you have learned to become one with the shadows. When you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible. You remain invisible until 

you make an attack, cast a spell, or are in an area of bright light.</p>
</description><sheet action="Action"><description>When you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can become invisible. You remain invisible until you make an attack, cast a spell, 

or are in an area of bright light.</description></sheet></element><element name="Opportunist" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_SHADOW_OPPORTUNIST" source="Daniel Variants" 

type="Archetype Feature"><description>
<p>At 17th level, you can exploit a creature’s momentary distraction when it is hit by an attack. Whenever a creature within 5 feet of you is hit by an attack made by a creature other than 

you, you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against that creature. If you are in dim light or darkness you can then immediately use your shadow step feature as part of the same 

reaction.</p>
</description><sheet action="Reaction"><description>Whenever a creature within 5 feet of you is hit by an attack made by a creature other than you, you can make a melee attack against that 

creature. If you are in dim light or darkness you can then immediately use your shadow step feature as part of the same reaction.</description></sheet></element>

<element name="Way of the Four Elements" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_MONK_WAY_OF_THE_FOUR_ELEMENTS" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype"><supports>VARMonastic 

Tradition</supports><description>
<p>You follow a monastic tradition that teaches you to harness the elements. When you focus your ki, you can align yourself with the forces of creation and bend the four elements to your 

will, using them as an extension of your body. Some members of this tradition dedicate themselves to a single element, but others weave the elements together.</p>
<p class="indent">Many monks of this tradition tattoo their bodies with representations of their ki powers, commonly imagined as coiling dragons, but also as phoenixes, fish, plants, 

mountains, and cresting waves.</p>
<div element="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_FOUR_ELEMENTS_DISCIPLE_OF_THE_ELEMENTS"/>
</description><sheet display="false"><description>You follow a monastic tradition that teaches you to harness the elements.</description></sheet>
<rules><grant id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_FOUR_ELEMENTS_DISCIPLE_OF_THE_ELEMENTS" type="Archetype Feature" level="3"/></rules></element>
<element name="Disciple of the Elements" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_THE_FOUR_ELEMENTS_DISCIPLE_OF_THE_ELEMENTS" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><description>
<p>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you learn magical disciplines that harness the power of the four elements. A discipline requires you to spend ki points each time you use 

it.</p>
<p class="indent">You know the Elemental Attunement discipline and two other elemental disciplines of your choice, which are detailed in the “Elemental Disciplines” section below. In 

addition you know one of the following cantrips: Shape Water, Mold Earth, Control Flames or Gust. You learn two additional elemental disciplines and one of these elemental cantrips of your 

choice at 6th, 11th, and 17th level.</p>
<p class="indent">Whenever you finish a long rest, you can also replace one elemental discipline (other than elemental attunement) that you already know with a different discipline.</p>
<p class="indent"><strong><em>Casting Elemental Spells.</em></strong> Some elemental disciplines allow you to cast spells. To cast one of these spells, you use its casting time and other 

rules, but you don’t need to provide material components for it.</p>
<p class="indent">Once you reach 5th level in this class, you can spend additional ki points to increase the level of an elemental discipline spell that you cast, provided that the spell 

has an enhanced effect at a higher level, as burning hands does. The spell’s level increases by 1 for each additional ki point you spend. For example, if you are a 5th-level monk and use 

Sweeping Cinder Strike to cast burning hands, you can spend 2 ki points to cast it as a 2nd-level spell (the discipline’s base cost of 1 ki points plus 1).</p>
<p class="indent">The maximum number of ki points you can spend to cast a spell in this way (including its base ki point cost and any additional ki points you spend to increase its level) 

is determined by your monk level, as shown in the Spells and Ki Points table.</p>
<h5 class="caption">SPELLS AND KI POINTS</h5>
<table><thead>
<tr>
<td>Monk Levels</td>	<td>Maximum Ki Points for a Spell</td>
</tr></thead>
<tr>
<td>5th—8th</td>	<td><em>3</em></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>9th—12th</td>	<td><em>4</em></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>13th—16th</td>	<td><em>5</em></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>17th—20th</td>	<td><em>6</em></td>
</tr></table>
</description><sheet usage="Ki"><description>You learn magical disciplines that harness the power of the four elements.</description><description level="5">You can spend additional ki 

points (max 3) to increase the level of an elemental discipline spell that you cast. The spell’s level increases by 1 for each additional ki point you spend.</description><description 

level="9">You can spend additional ki points (max 4) to increase the level of an elemental discipline spell that you cast. The spell’s level increases by 1 for each additional ki point you 

spend.</description><description level="13">You can spend additional ki points (max 5) to increase the level of an elemental discipline spell that you cast. The spell’s level increases by 

1 for each additional ki point you spend.</description><description level="17">You can spend additional ki points (max 6) to increase the level of an elemental discipline spell that you 

cast. The spell’s level increases by 1 for each additional ki point you spend.</description></sheet>
<rules><grant id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_ELEMENTAL_ATTUNEMENT" type="Archetype Feature"/>
<select name="Elemental Discipline (Level 3)" type="Archetype Feature" number = "2" supports="VARElemental Discipline" level="3"/>

<select name="Elemental Discipline (Level 6)" type="Archetype Feature" number = "2" supports="VARElemental Discipline" level="6"/>

<select name="Elemental Discipline (Level 11)" type="Archetype Feature" number = "2" supports="VARElemental Discipline" level="11"/>

<select name="Elemental Discipline (Level 17)" type="Archetype Feature" number = "2" supports="VARElemental Discipline" level="17"/>  
<select name="Elemental Cantrip (Level 3)" type="Archetype Feature" supports="Elemental Cantrip" level="3"/>

<select name="Elemental Cantrip(Level 6)" type="Archetype Feature"  supports="Elemental Cantrip" level="6"/>

<select name="Elemental Cantrip(Level 11)" type="Archetype Feature"  supports="Elemental Cantrip" level="11"/>

<select name="Elemental Cantrip(Level 17)" type="Archetype Feature"  supports="Elemental Cantrip" level="17"/>  </rules></element>
<!-- Elemental Disciplines -->
<element name="Elemental Attunement" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_ELEMENTAL_ATTUNEMENT" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><description>
<p>You can use your action to briefly control elemental forces within 30 feet of you, causing one of the following effects of your choice:</p>
<ul>
•	<li>Create a harmless, instantaneous sensory effect related to air, earth, fire, or water, such as a shower of sparks, a puff of wind, a spray of light mist, or a gentle rumbling 

of stone.</li>
•	<li>Instantaneously light or snuff out a candle, a torch, or a small campfire.</li>
•	<li>Chill or warm up to 1 pound of nonliving material for up to 1 hour.</li>
•	<li>Cause earth, fire, water, or mist that can fit within a 1-foot cube to shape itself into a crude form you designate for 1 minute.</li>
</ul>
</description><sheet action="Action"><description>You can briefly control elemental forces within 30 feet of you.</description></sheet></element>
<element name="Barricade of the Sea" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_BARRICADE_OF_THE_SEA" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:11]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 11th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 4 ki points to cast Wall of Water.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_POTA_SPELL_WALLOFWATER"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 4 ki points to cast Wall of Water.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_POTA_SPELL_WALLOFWATER" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Breath of Winter" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_BREATH_OF_WINTER" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:17]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 17th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 6 ki points to cast cone of cold.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONE_OF_COLD"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 6 ki points to cast cone of cold.</description></sheet><rules>
<!-- remove from known spells but allow modded spellcards for reference -->
<grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONE_OF_COLD" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Clench of the North Wind" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_CLENCH_OF_THE_NORTH_WIND" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype 

Feature"><supports>VARElemental Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:6]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 6th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 2 ki points to cast hold person.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 2 ki points to cast hold person.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Dance of the burning blade" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_DANCE_OF_THE_BURNING_BLADE" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype 

Feature"><supports>VARElemental Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:6]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 6th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 3 ki points to cast flame blade.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_BLADE"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 3 ki points to cast flameblade.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_BLADE" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Eternal Mountain Defense" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_ETERNAL_MOUNTAIN_DEFENSE" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype 

Feature"><supports>VARElemental Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:17]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 17th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 5 ki points to cast stoneskin, targeting yourself.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 5 ki points to cast stoneskin, targeting yourself.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN" 

type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Fangs of the Fire Snake" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_FANGS_OF_THE_FIRE_SNAKE" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype 

Feature"><supports>VARElemental Discipline</supports><description>
<p>When you make an attack on your turn, you can spend 1 ki point to cause tendrils of flame to stretch out from your fists and feet. Your reach with your unarmed strikes increases by 10 

feet for that attack, as well as the rest of the turn. A hit with such an attack deals fire damage instead of bludgeoning damage, and if you spend 1 ki point when the attack hits, it also 

deals an extra 1d10 fire damage.</p>
</description><sheet><description>When you make an attack on your turn, you can spend 1 ki point to cause tendrils of flame to stretch out from your fists and feet. Your reach with your 

unarmed strikes increases by 10 feet for that attack, as well as the rest of the turn. A hit with such an attack deals fire damage instead of bludgeoning damage, and if you spend 1 ki 

point when the attack hits, it also deals an extra 1d10 fire damage.</description></sheet></element>
<element name="Feather in the air" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_FEATHER_IN_THE_AIR" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><description>
<p>You can spend 1 ki point to cast featherfall</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 1 ki point to cast featherfall</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Fist of Four Thunders" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_FIST_OF_FOUR_THUNDERS" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><description>
<p>You can spend 1 ki point to cast thunderwave</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDERWAVE"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 1 ki point to cast thunderwave</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDERWAVE" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Fist of Unbroken Air" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_FIST_OF_UNBROKEN_AIR" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><description>
<p>You can create a blast of compressed air that strikes like a mighty fist. As an action, you can spend 1 ki point and choose a creature within 30 feet of you. That creature must make a 

Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 2d10 bludgeoning damage, plus an extra 1d10 bludgeoning damage for each additional ki point you spend, and you can push the 

creature up to 20 feet away from you and knock it prone. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage, and you don’t push it or knock it prone.</p>
</description><sheet action="Action"><description>You can spend 1 ki point and choose a creature within 30 feet of you. That creature must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, 

the creature takes 2d10 bludgeoning damage, plus an extra 1d10 bludgeoning damage for each additional ki point you spend, and you can push the creature up to 20 feet away from you and 

knock it prone. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage, and you don’t push it or knock it prone.</description></sheet></element>
<element name="Flames of the Phoenix" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_FLAMES_OF_THE_PHOENIX" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:11]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 11th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 4 ki points to cast fireball.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIREBALL"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 4 ki points to cast fireball.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIREBALL" type="Spell"/></rules></element>

<element name="Fortress of air" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_FORTRESS_OF_AIR" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:11]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 11th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 4 ki points to cast Wind Wall.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALL"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 4 ki points to cast Wind Wall.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALL" type="Spell"/></rules></element>


<element name="fury of the mountain" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_FURY_OF_THE_MOUNTAIN" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:11]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 11th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 4 ki points to cast erupting earth.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ERUPTING_EARTH"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 4 ki points to cast erupting earth.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_ERUPTING_EARTH" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Gong of the Summit" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_GONG_OF_THE_SUMMIT" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:6]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 6th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 2 ki points to cast shatter.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 2 ki points to cast shatter.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Mist Stance" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_MIST_STANCE" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:11]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 11th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 4 ki points to cast gaseous form, targeting yourself.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_GASEOUS_FORM"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 4 ki points to cast gaseous form, targeting yourself.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GASEOUS_FORM" 

type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Raft upon the current" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_RAFT_UPON_THE_CURRENT" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:6]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 6th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 2 ki points to cast water walk or water breathing, targeting yoursel.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_WALK"/>
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_BREATHING"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 2 ki points to cast water walk or water breathing targeting yourself.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_WALK" 

type="Spell"/><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WATER_BREATHING" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Redirect the Elements" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_REDIRECT THE ELEMENTS" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><description>
<p>You can spend 1 ki point to cast absorb elements</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_POTA_SPELL_ABSORBELEMENTS"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 1 ki point to cast absorb elements</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_POTA_SPELL_ABSORBELEMENTS" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Ride the Wind" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_RIDE_THE_WIND" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:11]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 11th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 4 ki points to cast fly, targeting yourself.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 4 ki points to cast fly, targeting yourself.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLY" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="River of Hungry Flame" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_RIVER_OF_HUNGRY_FLAME" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:17]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 17th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 5 ki points to cast wall of fire.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 5 ki points to cast wall of fire.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Rush of the Gale Spirits" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_RUSH_OF_THE_GALE_SPIRITS" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype 

Feature"><supports>VARElemental Discipline</supports><description>
<p>You can spend 1 ki point to cast gust of wind.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST_OF_WIND"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 1 ki points to cast gust of wind.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST_OF_WIND" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Sculpture of the Giant Badger" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_SCULPTURE_OF_THE_GIANT_BADGER" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype 

Feature"><supports>VARElemental Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:17]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 17th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 6 ki points to cast stoneshape.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONE_SHAPE"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 6 ki points to cast Stoneshape.</description></sheet><rules>
<grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONE_SHAPE" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Shape the Flowing River" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_SHAPE_THE_FLOWING_RIVER" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype 

Feature"><supports>VARElemental Discipline</supports><description>
<p>As an action, you can spend 1 ki point to choose a area no larger than 60ft on each side that contains at least some water or ice and that is within 90 feet of you. You can change water 

to ice within the area and vice versa, and you can reshape ice in the area in any manner you choose. You can raise or lower the ice’s elevation, create or fill in a trench, erect or 

flatten a wall, or form a pillar. The extent of any such changes can’t exceed 30 ft. For example, you can create a pillar up to 30 feet high, raise or lower the square’s elevation by up to 

30 feet, dig a trench up to 30 feet deep, and so on, given that there is enough water or ice in the area. You can’t shape the ice to trap or injure a creature in the area.</p>
</description><sheet action="Action"><description> You can spend 1 ki point to choose an area no larger than 60ft on each side that contains at least some water or ice (range 90 feet). You 

can change water to ice within the area and vice versa, and you can reshape ice in the area in any manner you choose. You can’t shape the ice to trap or injure a creature in the 

area.</description></sheet></element>
<element name="Stone Prison" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_STONE_PRISON" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><description>
<p>. You can spend 1 Ki point as an action to envelop a creature within stone. A creature you can see within 30ft of you must make a strength saving throw. On a failed save the creature takes 2d10 bludgeoning damage, plus an extra 1d10 bludgeoning damage for each additional Ki point you spend and is restrained until the end of its next turn. On a successful save the creature takes half as much damage and is not restrained.</p>
</description><sheet action="Action"><description>. You can spend 1 Ki point as an action to envelop a creature within stone. A creature you can see within 30ft of you must make a strength saving throw. On a failed save the creature takes 2d10 bludgeoning damage, plus an extra 1d10 bludgeoning damage for each additional Ki point you spend and is restrained until the end of its next turn. On a successful save the creature takes half as much damage and is not restrained.</description></sheet></element>
<element name="Sweeping Cinder Strike" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_SWEEPING_CINDER_STRIKE" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><description>
<p>You can spend 1 ki point to cast burning hands.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_BURNING_HANDS"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 1 ki point to cast burning hands.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BURNING_HANDS" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="The sleeping stone" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_THE_SLEEPING_STONE" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:11]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 11th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 4 ki points to cast meld into stone.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_MELD_INTO_STONE"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 4 ki points to cast meld into stone.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MELD_INTO_STONE" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Water Whip" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_WATER_WHIP" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><description>
<p>You can spend 1 ki point as an action to create a whip of water that shoves and pulls a creature to unbalance it. A creature that you can see that is within 30 feet of you must make a 

Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 2d10 bludgeoning damage, plus an extra 1d10 bludgeoning damage for each additional ki point you spend, and you can knock it 

prone and pull it up to 25 feet closer to you. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage, and you don’t pull it or knock it prone.</p>
</description><sheet action="Action"><description>You can spend 1 ki point to create a whip of water that shoves and pulls a creature to unbalance it. A creature that you can see that is 

within 30 feet of you must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 2d10 bludgeoning damage, plus an extra 1d10 bludgeoning damage for each additional ki point 

you spend, and you can knock it prone and pull it up to 25 feet closer to you. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage, and you don’t pull it or knock it 

prone.</description></sheet></element>
<element name="Water in the Wind" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_WATER_IN_THE_WIND" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:17]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 17th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 6 ki points to cast Watery Sphere.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_POTA_SPELL_WATERYSPHERE"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 6 ki points to cast Watery Sphere.</description></sheet><rules>
<!-- remove from known spells but allow modded spellcards for reference -->
<grant id="ID_POTA_SPELL_WATERYSPHERE" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Wave of Rolling Earth" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_WAVE_OF_ROLLING_EARTH" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:17]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 17th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 6 ki points to cast wall of stone.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_STONE"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 6 ki points to cast wall of stone.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_STONE" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Whirl of the dragonfly" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_DISCIPLINE_WHIRL_OF_THE_DRAGONFLY" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>VARElemental 

Discipline</supports><requirements>[level:6]</requirements><description>
<p><em>Prerequisite: 6th level</em></p>
<p>You can spend 2 ki points to cast warding wind.</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_POTA_SPELL_WARDINGWIND"/>
</div>
</description><sheet><description>You can spend 2 ki points to cast warding wind.</description></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_POTA_SPELL_WARDINGWIND" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Shape Water" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_CANTRIP_SHAPE_WATER" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>Elemental 

Cantrip</supports><description>
<p>You learn the Shape Water Cantrip</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_POTA_SPELL_SHAPEWATER"/>
</div>
</description><sheet></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_POTA_SPELL_SHAPEWATER" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Mold Earth" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_CANTRIP_MOLD_EARTH" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>Elemental 

Cantrip</supports><description>
<p>You learn the Mold Earth Cantrip</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_POTA_SPELL_MOLDEARTH"/>
</div>
</description><sheet></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_POTA_SPELL_MOLDEARTH" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Control Flames" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_CANTRIP_CONTROL_FLAME" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>Elemental 

Cantrip</supports><description>
<p>You learn the Control Flames Cantrip</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_POTA_SPELL_CONTROLFLAMES"/>
</div>
</description><sheet></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_POTA_SPELL_CONTROLFLAMES" type="Spell"/></rules></element>
<element name="Gust" id="ID_TORAD_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ELEMENTAL_CANTRIP_GUST" source="Daniel Variants" type="Archetype Feature"><supports>Elemental Cantrip</supports><description>
<p>You learn the Gust Cantrip</p>
<div class="reference">
<div element="ID_POTA_SPELL_GUST"/>
</div>
</description><sheet></sheet><rules><grant id="ID_POTA_SPELL_GUST" type="Spell"/></rules></element></elements>

